# **Keenan Mapp**

34-20 Parsons Boulevard, Apartment 1P Flushing, New York 11354

EMAIL: keenan560@gmail.com MOBILE: (718) 344-3951

#### SENIOR FINANCIAL SERVICES ASSOCIATE

A committed professional with 7 years of combined experiences in the financial services industry, particularly from major financial institutions in the Consumer & Corporate Investment Banking divisions. Proven areas of expertise include relationship building, data analysis, compliance, operations and business development. Especially effective at problem solving, decision making, performing audits, database querying, and metrics reporting. Characterized as adaptable, pro-active, and resourceful. Strong skills include verbal and written communication, research, and assessment. Key accomplishments include: Significant reduction in portion of portfolio susceptible to levies, and the creation of application processes and tools. Background also includes knowledge of the bankruptcy, banking and securities industries. Areas of expertise span a comprehensive range of functions.

- Compliance
- Analytics
- SQL
- Project Management
- Financial Modeling
- Team oriented
- Interpersonal
- Problem Solver
- Audit
- Bankruptcy Code
- Quick-learner
- Research

#### **AWARDS & RECOGNITION**

Placed top five in Penn State Smeal College of Business 2009 Global Trading Competition

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Expense Processing Temp**

The Goldman Sachs Group Inc., New York, NY

Oct 2017 to Nov 2018

- Work together with administrative assistants and investment bankers in order to reconcile a variety of client related expenses.
- Research and investigate transactions to ensure compliance within firm guidelines.
- Escalate processing related issues to management.
- Pioneered an Expense Overview template to provide management with color in their decision making.
- Utilize Business Intelligence tools like Oracle to study data and create reports.

## **Program Support Assistant Temp**

Jun 2017 to Sept 2017

Fitch Learning, New York, NY

- Assist Instructors with administering training programs onsite for major financial institutions.
- Provide feedback on analysts in areas such as Excel, Accountability, Presentation, Focus, and Meritocracy.
- Escalated, researched, and resolved issues pertaining to trading simulations, exam portals, and curriculum.
- Distributed and presented progress reports in Excel using Functions like V-LOOKUP, INDEX, IF Statements, Conditional Formatting, PIVOT, MIN, MAX, AVG, etc.

## **Accounting Temp**

May 2017 to Jun 2017

# Institute for Building Technology and Safety, Brooklyn, NY

- Responsible for identifying and explaining inconsistencies with invoices between contractors and the City of New York.
- Organized the company's records management system in order to meet City government standards.
- Charged with training and managing other temps with their workflows.

Keenan Mapp Page 2 of 2

#### **Senior Operations Associate**

Feb 2014 to Jul 2016

#### J.P. Morgan Securities LLC, New York, NY

- Successfully preserved qualifications with 44 US states by maintaining regulatory relationships, partnering with surety bond agents, and reporting data analytics.
- Scored 100% on all state regulatory license examinations by using extensive research skills, accurate database querying, and attention to detail.
- Achieved a first-rate grade 16 months consecutively from internal auditors on all sworn documents metrics reporting by means of due diligence and consistent execution of procedures.
- Raised the group's BBB rating four grades by synchronizing senior management's objectives with BBB prerequisites, analysis, and interpersonal skills.
- Partnered with different groups within the Corporate Investment Bank (Global Securitized Products Middle Office, Maxis IT Support, Legal, Corporate Tax, Corporate Secretary, Accounts Payable, Finance, and Compliance) in order to solve a wide array of issues.
- Drafted new policy and procedures as required by clients, internal counsel, and changes in the environment.
- Distributed and clarified KPIs on a monthly basis to vendors and senior management.
- Worked closely with external and legal counsel in order to review, edit, and approve various legal documents including Purchase Agreements and Responses to Complaints.
- Accountable for identifying and assessing legal and operational risks to the business, while monitoring the effectiveness of their solution.

#### **Relationship Banker Small Business Specialist**

Aug 2010 to Feb 2014

### J.P. Morgan Chase & Co., New York, NY

- Reviewed financial statements of companies and affluent individuals (over 300) (10-K, 10-Q, 401k, brokerage, mutual funds).
- Pitched and sold clients on investment solutions including senior executives of fortune 500 companies.
- Advised clients on methods to improve cash flows and liquidity for their day to day operations.
- Established rapport with clients by gaining product knowledge, meeting demands, and servicing their needs.
- Created budgeting plans for individuals in order to achieve savings and spending goals.
- Added value to local communities by conducting financial literacy workshops.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Columbia University**, New York, NY **Engineering Coding Bootcamp** - Full Stack Web Developer

Graduation Oct 2019

## **Investment Banking Institute**

## Intensive 4-week financial modeling and valuation training program

- Completed October 2015
- Performed company valuations utilizing (i) comparable company analysis, (ii) precedent transactions analysis and (iii) discounted cash flow analysis (DCF) analysis.
- Built fully-integrated financial statements projection model, LBO model, accretion/dilution merger models, including ability to run operational and capital structure sensitives within models and data tables for sensitivity analysis.

**Pennsylvania State University**, University Park, PA **Bachelors of Science** - Economics

Graduated May 2010